<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food Wednesday on Not So Fungible</title>
    <link>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/tags/food-wednesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food Wednesday on Not So Fungible</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 15:30:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jamieduerden.me/tags/food-wednesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Cassoulet</title>
      <link>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-cassoulet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-cassoulet/</guid>
      <description>I promised quite a long time ago, now, to give you all the rest of my recipe for not-actually-cassoulet. The confit duck legs of the previous recipe are one component of this; today you get the rest. Lucky you! I suggest you do the legs first since they need several days to mature.
The topping on this variant happens to be gluten-free, which was originally just because a friend of mine has this habit of getting rather ill when she eats bread, but turned out to be a rather tasty alternative to breadcrumbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Duck Confit</title>
      <link>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-duck-confit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 20:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-duck-confit/</guid>
      <description>This one was actually done on a Sunday, but you&amp;rsquo;re getting it on Wednesday because how else does one maintain a new tradition?
Confit duck leg isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly complex, though there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit in the sauce here, but it&amp;rsquo;s delicious and sounds impressive, if that&amp;rsquo;s something you go for in your food. Duck itself is a fairly versatile meat, so long as you don&amp;rsquo;t overwhelm the flavour. In this instance it&amp;rsquo;s paired with orange, which is classic, but there are an awful lot of options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Pork Fillet &amp; Figs</title>
      <link>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-pork-fillet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 23:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-pork-fillet/</guid>
      <description>This week, someone else&amp;rsquo;s hands were doing the cooking, so I could and did remember to take photographs. Credit due Fiona for this one; we don&amp;rsquo;t know where the recipe originated. Lateness due to difficulties in actually retrieving said photographs.
Pork Fillet with Figs and Tallegio - Serves three. Two if you&amp;rsquo;re hungry. Four if you&amp;rsquo;re small.
Ingredients
 One whole pork fillet 6-8 dried figs ~125ml dry sherry 150g Tallegio D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Pulled Pork &#39;Arancini&#39;</title>
      <link>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-pulled-pork-arancini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday-pulled-pork-arancini/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those recipes where I can sort of see how it came into being, but it&amp;rsquo;s a long way from its starting points. The rice preparation is sushi base, the pulled pork goes well in sandwiches, arancini are Italian. Culturally horrifying? Sure. So sue me, it tastes great. Anyone not convinced about bacon, halloumi, mango and black pepper, just try it - it&amp;rsquo;s a great salad all by itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Veal and Sweet Potato Pie</title>
      <link>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 19:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jamieduerden.me/post/food-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do recipes on Wednesdays, because routine is comforting and food is important. Or the other way around, I can never remember.
It was wet, cold, and dark all day today, so despite it being Summer I thought Winter food entirely appropriate. In that spirit I hunted in the freezer, and discovered we had some veal mince. Veal, for those of you not familiar, is young beef - it&amp;rsquo;s tender and sweet, without the heavy beef flavour, much as lamb compares to hogget or mutton.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>